Guide to the Bayrd Still Papers MC.44
New York University Archives
- Series V: Correspondence, 1949-1985; 1962-1977
  - Subseries B: NYC Research
    - O. Lewis: Random House, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 43)
    - Literary Digest: Time Magazine(?), 1970 (Box 54, Folder 44)
    - Literary Digest, City Auto National Munic Review 1920, undated (Box 54, Folder 45)
    - Locke, Albert and Charles Boni, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 46)
    - MacKay: John Murray Publishers, Ltd., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 47)
    - Mailer: New York Times Co., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 48)
    - Marshall: Law, Marston, & Co., Ltd., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 49)
    - McGraw-Hill News, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 50)
    - McKee: North American Review, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 51)
    - Moses, Harper and Brothers, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 52)
    - Moynihan. Public Interest 1969, 1972-1973 (Box 54, Folder 53)
    - Mumford: Harper and Row Publishers, Inc., 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 54)
    - The New York Times, 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 55)
    - Quincy: Mass. Hist. Society, 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 56)
    - Rainwater in Moynihan, ed. Basic Books, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 57)
    - Royko, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 58)
    - Saunders, Fortune, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 59)
    - Schaeffer. National Munic. Review, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 60)
    - Shelby: Harper and Row Publishers, 1970-1972 (Box 54, Folder 61)
    - So. Carolina Gazette - U. of S.C. Press, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 62)
    - Stein: Van Nostrand Reinbold Publishing Co., 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 63)
    - Stouffer - National Civic Review, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 64)
    - Strong: Macmillan Co., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 65)
    - Survey, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 66)
    - Tabor. Forest Hills Report, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 67)
    - Time Jan. 31, 1969, 1972-1973 (Box 54, Folder 68)
    - A. Trollope, Harper & Row Publishers, Inc., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 69)
    - Twain, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 70)
    - Wagner - Open Letter, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 71)
    - Weaver: Current History, Inc., 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 72)
    - US News & World Report, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 73)
    - Whyte: Doubleday and Co., Inc., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 74)
    - Wilhelm - Alfred A. Knopf, 1970-1973 (Box 54, Folder 75)
    - Wilson: Farrar, Straus & Giroux W.H. Allen & Co. Ltd., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 76)
    - Zeckendorf: Little, Brown & Co., 1970-1972 (Box 54, Folder 77)
    - Zueblin: Macmillan Co., 1970 (Box 54, Folder 78)
    - Little Brown Royalty Info, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225100 2
    - Little Brown-Promotional Materials, 1974-1976 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Kathleen Field Re Credits, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Abzug - correspondence, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Comment on book, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Otaguro, 1972-1974 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Books sent to, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Little, Brown & Co., 1972-1974 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Expenditures for Urban America, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Suggestions for Reading, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Comment of readers, 1970, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Style Sheet - City Book, undated (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Lincoln Center Program, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Whitman, Walt - City of Ships, undated (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Whitman, Walt - City of Ships, undated (Box 55, Folder 15)
- Series VI: Landmarks, 1957-1983
  Series VI contains correspondence, articles, press releases, reports, minutes, and calendars concerning the landmarks marking project of the New York Community Trust, the Committee for the Preservation of Structures of Historical and Esthetic Importance, and the Landmarks Preservation Commission. Most of the correspondence is between Still and Ralph Hayes, the executive director of New York Community Trust. Additional correspondence includes letters from the graduate fellows, which closed to researchers.
  Photos from two reports regarding United State Presidents and United States Vice-Presidents were separated and added to the University Archives photo collection.
  - History, 1978 Apr. 11 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225101 0
  - Correspondence, Press release, Articles, 1957-1962 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1965 Jan. - 1965 Sep. (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1965 Sep.- 1966 Sep. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1966 Oct. - 1967 Aug. (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1967 Aug. - 1970 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Kramer Research on Literary Figures, 1965 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225102 8
  - Report on New York City Residences of United States Presidents, 1963 July 22 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - List of Plaques, List of threatened and destroyed buildings, Designated New York City Landmarks, 1964-1967 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1964 Sep. - 1964 Oct. (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commision: History, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225103 6
  - Committee for the Preservation of Structures of Historical and Esthetic Importance--Minutes and Recommendations, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Minutes, Designation, Press Release, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Heights Association--Proposal for designation of Historic district, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Minutes, designation, maps, 1963 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Minutes, designation, maps, 1964-1965 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - New York City Council for Landmarks Preservation, Press Release, 1964 Dec. 12 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, Statutes drafts, articles concerning Landmarks Preservation Bill & Copy of Enacted Law, 1964-1965 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Landmarks Preservation: Index to Law, Amendments,City Record, 1965 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, 1965 Sep. - 1967 Feb. (Box 59, Folder 1)
    3 1142 04225104 4
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, 1969 Jan. - 1977 Jan. (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, 1977 Feb.- 1978 Feb. (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, 1978 Mar. - 1979 Mar. (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, 1979 May - 1980 May (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, 1980 Jul. - 1981 Nov. (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Landmark News, 1981 Nov. - 1983 Aug. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Calendars, Press Releases, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - George Clinton and Daniel Tompkins, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    Not offsite/ Part of Photograph Collection
- Series VII: Copper Photo Engravings, circa 1800s (Box 60, Box 61, Box 62, Box 63)
  This series is comprised of four boxes containing 47 copper engravings individually mounted on wood blocks. Prints created from these engravings were included in Still's book, Mirror for Gotham, which was published by New York University Press in 1956.
- Series VIII: Books on New York City and Urban America, 1969-1975
  Series VIII contains annotated books given to the University Archives by Bayrd Still.
  - A Season in New York, 1801: Letters of Harriet and Maria Trumbull, edited by Helen M. Morgan. Pittsburgh, PA: University of Pittsburgh Press., 1969 (Volume 1)
  - Running Against the Machine: A grass roots race for the New York mayoralty, edited by Peter Manso, Garden City, NY: Doubleday & Co., 1969 (Volume 2)
  - Keepers of the Gate: A History of Ellis Island, by Thomas Monroe Pitkin, New York: New York University Press, 1975 (Volume 3)
  - The Shame of the Cities, by Lincoln Steffens, New York: Hill and Wang, 1966 (Volume 4)
  - Urban America in Historical Perspective, edited by Raymond A. Mohl and Neil Betten, New York: Weybright and Talley, 1970 (Volume 5)